## Miguel Chito

## **Frontend Developer**

## **Summary**

#### Frontend Developer with a passion for innovation and creation.

I specialize in the MERN stack, REST API development, and core web technologies including JavaScript (ES6), React, Node.js, MongoDB, Express, HTML, and CSS. I excel in crafting dynamic and intuitive web applications that prioritize user experience.

With over a decade of experience in Graphic and Editorial Design, I bring a unique blend of artistic flair and technical expertise to my development projects. My diverse background, which includes time as a chef, has honed my skills in adaptability and attention to detail. This unique combination allows me to approach development challenges with a fresh perspective and an unwavering commitment to excellence.

#### **Education**

#### **Full Stack Web Developer Certification**

Ironhack 2024

- 3 months intensive Web Development Training | +400 hours. 3 big projects
- Built and deployed web apps based on MERN stack connected to REST API: HTML, CSS, JavaScript (ES6), React JS, Express.js, Node.js, MongoDB, Mongoose, Postman.
- Workflow using git and GitHub. Working with API designs.

#### **Food Production**

#### **Lisbon Culinary Arts School**

2014 - 2016

Manage kitchen operations, control kitchen service production costs.

#### Bachelor in Graphic and Editorial Design

#### **IADE - Lisbon Design University**

2004 - 2008

Higher University Education, Graphic and Editorial Design

#### Vocational and Technological College of Graphic Design

#### Lisbon Technological College of Graphic Design 2001 - 2004

Graphic Design, Visual Communication, Photography, Printing

(+45) 81121297

mchito@gmail.com
Copenhagen, Denmark

## **Projects**

#### MiniBookClub

Mini Book Club is a place where you can share notes of your favorite books and also ratings. It allows logged-in users to manage all the books, authors, and notes that they own in the database, doing full CRUD.

Full-stack application using the MERN stack (MongoDB, Express, React, and Node.JS)

#### **S** FounderFinder

Founder Finder is a web application where users can search for potential co-founders. It allows User Authentication, Search for Co-founders, Add New Ideas, Profile Management.

Full-stack application with MongoDB, Express, React, Node.js, TypeScript and Tailwind CSS

#### **𝚱** EventSlap

Full-stack application that allows logged-in users to manage all the events and venues that they own in the database, doing full CRUD.

SPA frontend, built with React, consisting of multiple views and implementing all CRUD actions for logged users.

REST API backend built with Express.js, MongoDB, and Mongoose.

## **Relevant Experience**

## **Graphic and Editorial Designer**

2015 - 2023

**Freelance** 

Remote/Lisbon

- Designed visually appealing graphics and layouts for various print and digital media.
- Focused on user experience and interface design, enhancing client satisfaction and engagement.

**Chef** 2021 - 2023

Kafetaria SMK

Copenhagen Art Museum

- Executed cost control, resulting in reduced food costs by 10%.
- Led team to achieve the highest customer satisfaction ratings in restaurant history.
- Cultivated a strong sense of creativity and adaptability, essential for innovative problem-solving in technology's

#### Work as chef in Southeast Asia

2016 - 2019

## India, Thailand, Laos, Cambodia, Vietnam, Indonesia

- Prepared traditional meals, emphasizing locally sourced ingredients.
- Adapted to diverse culinary environments, honing organizational and problem-solving skills.

# **Graphic Designer | Website Manager | Retouching Artist** 2011 - 2015

**Kasuar** Lisbon

- Collaborated with advertising agencies on diverse projects, ensuring quality control and rapid prototyping
- Back-office operations and updating website in a regular basis
- Managed multiple projects simultaneously, meeting tight deadlines and client expectations.

## **Volunteering**

#### Social Worker

2020 - 2022

#### **Danish Red Cross**

- Volunteer for the Danish Red Cross at the Avnstrup Asylum Center.
- The projects include gardening activities, child care, IT training.

## **∅** TopTravelTips

This project consists of multiple views, providing a user-friendly interface for exploring and sharing travel advice.

Single Page Application (SPA) using React. Integrated with an external API, the React application allows users to perform CRUD operations.

## Paperboy

Small remake of the 80s legendary paperboy arcade game.

Browser-based game created using vanilla HTML, CSS, JavaScript, DOM manipulation, and Object-Oriented Programming (OOP).

#### **Technical Skills**

MERN Stack | JavaScript(ES6) | React |
Node.js | Git | MongoDB | Express.js |
Mongoose | HTML5 | CSS3 | Bootstrap
| Tailwind CSS | Sass | Rest API |
Postman | GitHub. Chakra UI |
Semantic UI | Daisy UI | MUI UI | Ejs |
jQuery | SQL | PostgreSQL | Python |
Netlify | Firebase | Cloud Firestore |
Adaptable | Vercel | Motoko. |

Learning: Typescript and Next.js

#### **Certifications**

The Complete 2023 Web Development Bootcamp

Dr. Angela Yu, App Brewery

Project Management with Agile and Digital Methodologies

Talent Garden